Guide to the Thomas R. Hill Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Thomas R. Hill papers
1898-1900
WA MSS S-259
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.5
(1 box)
The papers consist of correspondence between Thomas R. Hill, Jennie M. Hill, Angelo Heilprin, and others, Thomas Hill's journal and drawings of gold mining in Alaska, and papers of the Philadelphia Exploration and Mining Company, which organized to mine in Alaska.
Hill, Thomas R.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Unspecified; please consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence between Thomas R. Hill, Jennie M. Hill, Angelo Heilprin, and others, Thomas Hill's journal and drawings of gold mining in Alaska, and papers of the Philadelphia Exploration and Mining Company, which organized to mine in Alaska.
Gold mines and mining -- Alaska; Alaska -- Pictorial works; Diaries -- United States; Drawings -- Pennsylvania; Gold miners -- Alaska; Heilprin, Angelo, 1853-1907; Hill, Jennie M.; Hill, Thomas R.; Philadelphia Exploration and Mining Company
- Box and Folder List
  Scope and Contents
  The collection is arranged alphabetically by author.
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Barstow, Lorene. ALS to Thomas R. Hill. Philadelphia?, 1898 Apr 20 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Beaman, George Bunham. ALS to Thomas R. Hill. Philadelphia?, 1898 Apr 16 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Beaman, Polly. ALS to Jennie Hill. Philadelphia?, 1898 Apr 16 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Blakiston, Mary. ALS to Thomas R. Hill. Philadelphia, 1898 Apr 7 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Heilprin, Angelo
      - ALS to Mrs. Thomas R. Hill. Philadelphia, 1898 Apr 6 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - 10 ALS to Thomas R. Hill. Philadelphia, 1898 Apr-May (Box 1, Folder 1)
        1898 Apr 7, 20, 24, 27(2), 28(2), 29, 30, May 9.
    - Hill, Jennie M.
      - ALS to Angelo Heilprin. West Creek, [1899?] Aug 12 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - ALS to Thomas R. Hill. Philadelphia, 1900 Jun 29 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Hill, Thomas R.
      - ALS to "Dear John." Tenana, Alaska, 1900 Jul 20 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - ALS to Jennie Hill. Tanana, Alaska, 1900 Jul 2 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - DIARIES AND JOURNALS
    - Notebook containing pencil sketches of Alaska scenery and notes on Alaska geology (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Sketch of his Alaska experiences, 1898 May-Oct (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Partly narrative, partly journal form. With: Miscellaneous unsorted papers, including newspaper clippings and a typed receipt for bank books, safe deposit keys, insurance commissions, etc.
    - Journal, 1899 Apr-Nov (Box 1, Folder 4)
      In bound Excelsior journal. Entries for many dates omitted.
  - MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS
    - Philadelphia exploration and mining company. Miscellaneous unsorted papers, inc.: Lists of supplies, notices to stockholders, etc., [1898?] (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Includes: Instructions to the leader of the expeditionary party ... [Philadelphia? 1898?]. Typescript. With this is bound "Exploration memorandum", Nos. 2-4. Also includes: Exploration Memorandum No. 2-4. Philadelphia, 1898. Typescript, part carbon.
    - Miscellaneous maps, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)